<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sound Motives - Where Music Meets Culture. on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sound Motives - Where Music Meets Culture. on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Episode 05 — Max Cooper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/episodes/ep-05-max-cooper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/episodes/ep-05-max-cooper/</guid>
      <description>Max Cooper — producer and visual-music collaborator — discusses his musical journey from his early days in Northern Ireland through academic research and experimental approaches to sound, sharing how eclectic influences shaped his philosophy and practice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 04 — Paul White</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/episodes/ep-04-paul-white/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/episodes/ep-04-paul-white/</guid>
      <description>Paul White reflects on his journey from the British beats scene and sampling heritage to traditional songwriting and broad artistic influences, discussing his evolution and creative philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 03 — Mala</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/episodes/ep-03-mala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/episodes/ep-03-mala/</guid>
      <description>Mala — DJ, producer, promoter, and co‑founder of Digital Mystikz — explores his early influences from jungle and dub to club culture, discussing the evolution of dubstep, the role of Deep Medi, and how his sound has developed over time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 02 — Kenton Slash Demon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/episodes/ep-02-kenton-slash-demon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/episodes/ep-02-kenton-slash-demon/</guid>
      <description>Silas Moldenhawer of Kenton Slash Demon discusses the duo’s origins, their early musical influences, approaches to sampling, the Copenhagen scene, and how remixes and collaborators shaped their work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode 01 — Shigeto</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/episodes/ep-01-shigeto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/episodes/ep-01-shigeto/</guid>
      <description>Zach ‘Shigeto’ Saginaw reflects on his musical beginnings — from Ann Arbor to Detroit — discussing how jazz, electronic music, and local scenes shaped his sound.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>411VM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/411vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/411vm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Growing up with ambitions to be a skateboard photographer, Paul initially discovered a lot of music through a monthly skateboarding video magazine called &lt;strong&gt;411VM&lt;/strong&gt;. Launched in 1993, 411VM profiled skateboarders from the US and across the world, with the skaters choosing the music for their video sections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because it reflected the breadth of global skateboard culture rather than specific scenes or brands, the range of music was unusually broad and formative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Sound Motives</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sound Motives is a long-form audio series exploring the musical influences that shape today’s most interesting artists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rather than focusing on releases or career milestones, each episode traces the deeper listening habits that sit behind an artist’s work — the records, scenes, sounds, and moments that helped form their creative perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guests are invited to reflect on the music that mattered to them at different points in their lives: formative records, pivotal cultural movements, and the sounds that continue to inform how they make music today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alan Watts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/alan-watts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/alan-watts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alan Watts (1915–1973) was one of the first writers and speakers to interpret Eastern philosophy for Western audiences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born near London, Watts discovered Buddhism at a young age before moving to the United States in 1938. He later became an Episcopal priest, relocated to Millbrook, New York, and authored &lt;em&gt;The Wisdom of Insecurity&lt;/em&gt;, one of his most influential works.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the 1950s onward, his radio talks and lectures gained national reach, and by the 1960s he had become an unlikely spiritual voice for the counterculture movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ali Farka Touré</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/ali-farka-toure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/ali-farka-toure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An eclectic mix of music was always present in Paul’s home growing up — from Weather Report and Crosby, Stills &amp;amp; Nash to Bobby Womack and Malian musician &lt;strong&gt;Ali Farka Touré&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 2002 documentary &lt;em&gt;A Visit to Ali Farka Touré&lt;/em&gt; captures the artist later in life, focusing on his humanitarian efforts in Mali and how his work increasingly centred on improving living conditions rather than recording and touring.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Touré’s commitment to community and place offers a powerful example of how artistic purpose can evolve beyond commercial output.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ann Arbor, Michigan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/ann-arbor-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/ann-arbor-michigan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Growing up in &lt;strong&gt;Ann Arbor, Michigan&lt;/strong&gt; has had a lasting influence on Zach Shigeto’s musical output.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The city appears frequently in the titles of his productions, and the landscapes of his hometown regularly feature in his photography, particularly on Instagram. Ann Arbor’s cultural environment — home to the University of Michigan and a strong jazz heritage — played a formative role in shaping his early creative identity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augustus Pablo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/augustus-pablo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/augustus-pablo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his teens, Mala discovered the music of &lt;strong&gt;Augustus Pablo&lt;/strong&gt;, the Jamaican melodica player and producer. Pablo’s subtle melodic flourishes and experimental approach to production deeply influenced Mala’s work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pablo’s innovations included early dub production, collaborations with &lt;strong&gt;King Tubby&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Lee “Scratch” Perry&lt;/strong&gt;, and the integration of drum machines with organic instrumentation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born Horace Swaby in 1954, Pablo’s career spanned from the mid-70s until his death in 1999, with the late 70s period widely regarded as his finest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axel Boman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/axel-boman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/axel-boman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Axel Boman&lt;/strong&gt; is a Swedish electronic music producer whose remixes of Kenton Slash Demon’s &lt;em&gt;Daemon&lt;/em&gt; in 2010 proved particularly influential.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both remixes were sparse, evolving, and hypnotic, showcasing Boman’s ability to create tension and movement with minimal elements. While known for club-ready releases, it is his more experimental work that most strongly resonated with Kenton Slash Demon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recent remixes for &lt;strong&gt;John Talabot&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Maribou State&lt;/strong&gt;, as well as his original work on &lt;strong&gt;DJ Koze’s Pampa Records&lt;/strong&gt;, continue to expand his sonic palette.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brian Blade — Fellowship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/brian-blade-fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/brian-blade-fellowship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shigeto moved east to attend college at &lt;strong&gt;The New School&lt;/strong&gt; in New York, where he continued developing as a jazz drummer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During this time, one of his biggest influences was &lt;strong&gt;Brian Blade&lt;/strong&gt;, particularly Blade’s 1998 album &lt;em&gt;Fellowship&lt;/em&gt; and the track &lt;em&gt;Folklore&lt;/em&gt;. Blade’s expressive, musical approach to drumming — prioritising feel, restraint, and emotional communication — had a profound impact on Shigeto’s playing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brian Blade continues to lead the Fellowship while also collaborating with artists such as &lt;strong&gt;Joni Mitchell&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Bob Dylan&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Wayne Shorter&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dabrye — One:Three</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/dabrye/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/dabrye/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While in high school, Shigeto discovered electronic music through his local label &lt;strong&gt;Ghostly International&lt;/strong&gt;, which exposed him to a wide range of experimental and left-field releases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Key records from this period included albums by &lt;strong&gt;Matthew Dear&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Lusine&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Midwest Product&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Charles Manier&lt;/strong&gt;, but the defining moment came with &lt;strong&gt;Dabrye’s &lt;em&gt;One:Three&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, released by Ghostly in June 2001.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The record bridged Shigeto’s jazz background with a new electronic sensibility, opening his ears to rhythm, texture, and production as compositional tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dark Matters Collective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/dark-matters-collective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/dark-matters-collective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dark Matters&lt;/strong&gt; are a visual collective who collaborated closely with Kenton Slash Demon on the &lt;em&gt;Schwarzschild Trilogy&lt;/em&gt; of EPs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As referenced in Episode 3, both the graphic designers and videographers involved in the project played a formative role in shaping the direction of the music itself, not merely its presentation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dark Matters have since worked with artists such as &lt;strong&gt;Den Sorte Skole&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Trentemøller&lt;/strong&gt;, often focusing on light projection and installation work — meaning that visuals which appear digitally generated are frequently physical, real-world constructions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depeche Mode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/depeche-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/depeche-mode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Growing up in Northern Ireland, the first electronic music Max encountered came via the late-1980s synth-pop movement. His sister was a fan of &lt;strong&gt;Depeche Mode&lt;/strong&gt; and Erasure, and their records provided an early gateway into electronic sound.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This exposure laid the groundwork for Max’s later interest in electronic music as an emotional and expressive medium, rather than purely functional club music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dubsided Records / Dave Taylor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/dubsided-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/dubsided-records/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Kenton Slash Demon’s first EP on Tartelet Records in 2009, the group were heavily influenced by the percussive sounds of UK label &lt;strong&gt;Dubsided&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run by producer &lt;strong&gt;Dave Taylor&lt;/strong&gt;, releasing under the aliases &lt;strong&gt;Switch&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Solid Groove&lt;/strong&gt;, Dubsided played a major role in reshaping house music in the late 2000s. The label helped popularise the playful, rhythm-driven sub-genre often referred to as &lt;em&gt;fidget house&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dubsided released music from &lt;strong&gt;Jesse Rose&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Sinden&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Hervé&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Trevor Loveys&lt;/strong&gt;, and early &lt;strong&gt;Duke Dumont&lt;/strong&gt;, leaving a lasting imprint on UK club culture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Drum &amp; Bass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/early-drum-and-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/early-drum-and-bass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arriving at university in Nottingham, Max was introduced to drum &amp;amp; bass at the legendary &lt;strong&gt;Marcus Garvey Centre&lt;/strong&gt;. It was his first experience of the genre in a club context.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Artists such as &lt;strong&gt;Mickey Finn&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Aphrodite&lt;/strong&gt;, along with labels like &lt;strong&gt;RAM Records&lt;/strong&gt;, retained some of the aesthetic qualities Max loved in rave culture while introducing a new level of rhythmic complexity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts such as &lt;strong&gt;Ed Rush &amp;amp; Optical&lt;/strong&gt; became particularly influential during this period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google NSynth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/google-nsynth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/google-nsynth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Technology plays a significant role in Max’s musical process, from experiments with binaural sound and Dolby Atmos to emerging approaches such as machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NSynth&lt;/strong&gt;, developed by Google, uses deep neural networks to generate sound at the level of individual samples. By analysing existing sounds and extracting their defining features, NSynth can interpolate between them to create entirely new timbres.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Max, NSynth represents a future where advanced sound design tools become widely accessible, opening new creative possibilities for artists beyond traditional synthesis methods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. Krishnamurti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/j-krishnamurti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/j-krishnamurti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jiddu Krishnamurti (1895–1986) was born in Madanapalle, India, and was raised under the belief that he would become a world spiritual teacher.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1929, he publicly rejected this role, dissolved the organisation created around him, and returned all donated property and funds. From then on, he spent nearly sixty years travelling internationally, speaking to large audiences about freedom, self-inquiry, and radical personal change.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His uncompromising approach to truth and awareness has influenced artists, thinkers, and creatives seeking clarity beyond doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jamie Woon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/jamie-woon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/jamie-woon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier in his career, Paul’s creative process was largely solitary — producing beats remotely for MCs. More recently, he began collaborating directly with musicians in shared studio spaces.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of those early face-to-face collaborations was with &lt;strong&gt;Jamie Woon&lt;/strong&gt; on the track &lt;em&gt;Thunder&lt;/em&gt; from Woon’s 2015 album &lt;em&gt;Making Time&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These sessions helped Paul develop new approaches to songwriting, lyrics, and collective creativity, highlighting the power of working closely with others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Coltrane</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/john-coltrane/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/john-coltrane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John Coltrane was a groundbreaking jazz saxophonist and composer whose innovative work reshaped the landscape of modern jazz. Renowned for his intense improvisations, spiritual depth, and technical mastery, Coltrane pushed musical boundaries with albums like Giant Steps and A Love Supreme. His relentless pursuit of musical exploration influenced generations of musicians and solidified his legacy as one of the most important figures in 20th-century music.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Coltrane — A Love Supreme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/john-coltrane-a-love-supreme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/john-coltrane-a-love-supreme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Growing up in Michigan, Zach Shigeto initially dreamed of becoming a professional jazz musician. A number of seminal jazz records formed the foundation of his musical education, including works by &lt;strong&gt;Pharoah Sanders&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Miles Davis&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Bill Evans&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Herbie Hancock&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among these, &lt;strong&gt;John Coltrane’s &lt;em&gt;A Love Supreme&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; stood apart. Recorded in late 1964 and released on Impulse! Records in 1965, the album’s spiritual intensity and rhythmic depth left a lasting impression on Shigeto’s approach to music — both as a drummer and later as a producer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jungle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/jungle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/jungle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A high‑energy, breakbeat‑driven music culture that prefigured dubstep — Mala’s first love, shaped by pirate radio and early UK underground communities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kahn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/kahn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/kahn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mala cites contemporary Bristol producer &lt;strong&gt;Kahn (Joseph McGann)&lt;/strong&gt; as a current influence. Kahn’s work spans dubstep, grime, and reggae/digital styles through projects including &lt;strong&gt;Kahn &amp;amp; Neek&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Bandulu Records&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Gorgon Sound&lt;/strong&gt;, and he is part of the &lt;strong&gt;Young Echo Collective&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kahn exemplifies Mala’s interest in artists who blend historical knowledge of bass music with fresh, authentic production.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kevin McGloughlin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/kevin-mcgloughlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/kevin-mcgloughlin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having experienced the power of combining sound with visuals early in his career, Max has frequently collaborated with visual artists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One such collaborator is &lt;strong&gt;Kevin McGloughlin&lt;/strong&gt;, a visual artist based in Sligo. McGloughlin’s extensive body of work explores light, motion, and abstraction, complementing Max’s interest in immersive audiovisual experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Their collaborations reflect a shared interest in blurring the boundaries between music, film, and installation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lusine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/lusine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/lusine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A musician Max cites as setting the benchmark for beautiful electronic music is &lt;strong&gt;Lusine&lt;/strong&gt;. Originally from Texas and later based in Seattle, Lusine has been releasing music since the early 1990s and has remained consistently prolific.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, he has also worked on film soundtracks, reinforcing the connection between electronic music and visual storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Max first encountered Lusine’s track &lt;em&gt;Jetstream&lt;/em&gt; through a LuckyMe mixtape by &lt;strong&gt;Claude Speeed&lt;/strong&gt;, only realising its identity years later while preparing this episode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo Kolours</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/mo-kolours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/mo-kolours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Paul has long shared an affinity with the South London label &lt;strong&gt;22a&lt;/strong&gt;, and for good reason — he has been close friends with members of the collective for over a decade.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of those artists is &lt;strong&gt;Joe ‘Mo Kolours’&lt;/strong&gt;, whose work Paul has greatly admired. Over the years, both producers have encouraged and motivated each other creatively, developing parallel approaches rooted in groove, texture, and intuition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitin Sawhney</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/nitin-sawhney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/nitin-sawhney/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nitin Sawhney&lt;/strong&gt; provided a contrasting perspective to Mala’s dancefloor-focused approach. Albums like &lt;em&gt;Beyond Skin&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Prophesy&lt;/em&gt; highlighted classical and electronic influences, blending Indian musical training with contemporary production.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sawhney’s multi-disciplinary approach — encompassing DJing, production, composition for film, TV, and symphony orchestras — offered Mala a model of versatility within a musical career.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obongjayar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/obongjayar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/obongjayar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent collaboration Paul has enjoyed is with rising artist &lt;strong&gt;Obongjayar&lt;/strong&gt; on the track &lt;em&gt;Adjacent Heart&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born in Nigeria, Steven Umoh grew up immersed in American hip-hop before moving to the UK, where he began questioning the authenticity of his adopted accent and persona. At university, he realised that embracing his natural Nigerian voice led him toward singing rather than rapping.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now recording as Obongjayar, his sound blends spoken word, electronic music, Afrobeat, and soul — resisting easy categorisation while remaining deeply personal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philip Glass / Koyaanisqatsi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/philip-glass-koyaanisqatsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/philip-glass-koyaanisqatsi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Max describes &lt;strong&gt;Philip Glass&lt;/strong&gt; as a major influence, particularly through his soundtrack work for &lt;em&gt;Koyaanisqatsi&lt;/em&gt; (1982), an experimental film that combines music and visuals without traditional narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Experiencing &lt;em&gt;Koyaanisqatsi&lt;/em&gt; was the first time Max fully felt the power of combining sound and image to create a heightened emotional experience. The repeating motifs and evolving intensity of Glass’s score, paired with Ron Fricke’s cinematography, revealed how multiple mediums could reinforce one another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reason</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/reason/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/reason/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After leaving college and moving to London, Shigeto developed tendonitis, preventing him from playing drums for several months. The injury led to a period of depression, but also marked a turning point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Encouraged by his brother, he began experimenting with music production instead of performance. Working with sequencers — particularly &lt;strong&gt;Reason&lt;/strong&gt; — opened up an entirely new creative pathway, ultimately leading to his debut &lt;em&gt;New Crossings&lt;/em&gt; EP in 2008.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This shift from physical performance to digital production reshaped Shigeto’s relationship with music and laid the foundation for his later work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steve Reich</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/steve-reich/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/steve-reich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kenton Slash Demon’s approach to sampling and repetition draws from a lineage that includes &lt;strong&gt;Daft Punk&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;J Dilla&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Madlib&lt;/strong&gt;, but the idea of slowly modulating looping material traces directly back to &lt;strong&gt;Steve Reich&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As early as the 1960s, Reich was experimenting with tape loops, phasing, and repetition. He later applied similar principles to live instrumentation, allowing performers to drift gradually in and out of sync, creating complex rhythmic interactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stones Throw Records</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/stones-throw-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/stones-throw-records/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After graduating from university, Paul moved back to London and began teaching music production at CM Sounds. During this period he became deeply influenced by the work of &lt;strong&gt;Madlib&lt;/strong&gt;, whose releases on &lt;strong&gt;Stones Throw Records&lt;/strong&gt; were a major inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Founded by Peanut Butter Wolf, Stones Throw developed a distinctive catalogue rooted in hip-hop, soul, jazz, and experimentation. The 2013 documentary &lt;em&gt;Our Vinyl Weighs a Ton&lt;/em&gt; chronicles the label’s history and cultural impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stormzy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/stormzy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/stormzy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking to the future, Mala acknowledges the next generation of UK artists, particularly &lt;strong&gt;Stormzy&lt;/strong&gt;, a grime MC from South London/Croydon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stormzy’s self-released freestyles and tracks, including becoming the first unsigned MC to perform on &lt;em&gt;Jools Holland&lt;/em&gt;, demonstrate the possibilities of innovation, longevity, and cultural reinvention — qualities Mala values in emerging artists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tartelet Records</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/tartelet-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/tartelet-records/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tartelet Records&lt;/strong&gt; is a Copenhagen-based label originally run by Emil Margetli Nyholm and Frederik Bille Brahe. It was at Tartelet that &lt;strong&gt;Kenton Slash Demon&lt;/strong&gt; developed their distinctive sound.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the years, the label has released influential music from artists such as &lt;strong&gt;Brandt Brauer Frick&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Max Graef&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Glenn Astro&lt;/strong&gt;, establishing itself as a hub for forward-thinking electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tartelet’s emphasis on atmosphere, restraint, and long-form development played a significant role in shaping Kenton Slash Demon’s early releases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Saints Go Machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/when-saints-go-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sound-sources/when-saints-go-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2007, Kenton Slash Demon joined forces with &lt;strong&gt;Simon Muschinsky&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Nikolaj Manuel Vonsild&lt;/strong&gt; to form the electro-pop band &lt;strong&gt;When Saints Go Machine&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Their later album &lt;em&gt;Infinity Pool&lt;/em&gt; blends electronic pop with emotional songwriting, drawing comparisons to &lt;strong&gt;Tears for Fears&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kanye West’s&lt;/em&gt; 808s &amp;amp; Heartbreak&lt;/em&gt;**, and features a guest appearance from &lt;strong&gt;Killer Mike&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Their performance at Roskilde Festival in 2013 marked a homecoming moment, with the festival having played an important role in their musical development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
